<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>babble</title><link>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/</link><description>Recent content on babble</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 09:38:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>003 Coffee</title><link>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/003-coffee/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 09:38:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/003-coffee/</guid><description>Coffee went from being something I knew about but had no experience with, to a daily ritual and something I have a real love for, in like the span of a couple months. It was freshman year of college, and the dining hall had free coffee, and I would take it with some cream and sugar. My friend Joe and I would kind of bond over coffee, I think he was already a coffee drinker and the reason I took an interest to it might have been a way to have something we could share and talk about.</description></item><item><title>002 - Education</title><link>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/002-education/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 22:02:36 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/002-education/</guid><description>I want to write about education because I think I bundle too many ideas into that word, and I want to tease them apart. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any coherent positions on &amp;ldquo;education&amp;rdquo; mostly because it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any crisp meaning in my head.
Ok, what are the concepts that I associate with the word &amp;ldquo;education&amp;rdquo;?
First is the school system in the United States. I get a sort of visual of lots of different school units spread over a large geography when I think of the term &amp;ldquo;education&amp;rdquo;, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s how my mind manifests the idea of the United States primary school system.</description></item><item><title>001 - Why am I writing?</title><link>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:04:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</guid><description>This is the first post in a 1,000 post project. A project to write a million words. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if those words are good, mediocre, amazing, or awful. It just matters that they exist. Because if they exist, it means I forced my brain to make a million words come out of my brain, through my fingers and the keyboard, into a computer, and onto the internet. And if that has happened, then I&amp;rsquo;ve probably learned a few things about myself, about writing, about consistency, about practice.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:04:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/about/</guid><description>This is a project to write 1,000,000 words.
I feel like I have a lot to say, both because there are things I want to share and because there are things I think I will only figure out through the course of writing.
But at the moment it&amp;rsquo;s difficult for me to get ideas out of my head and onto the page. The ideas in my head feel like water, and they are trying to flow downstream to the page, but the stream is not wide enough, or there is blockage, like sticks and leaves keeping the idea-water from moving quickly through the channel.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/archives/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/archives/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>