<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>babble</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/</link><description>Recent content on babble</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:14:14 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://babble.matthewroll.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>034 - Identity as a Writer</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/034-identity-as-a-writer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:14:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/034-identity-as-a-writer/</guid><description>What makes someone &amp;ldquo;a writer.&amp;rdquo; Like, being &amp;ldquo;a writer&amp;rdquo; is an occupation, certainly. If you have been paid for something you wrote then you can consider yourself a writer. Actually as I write that I realize that I have been paid for something I wrote: $100 BTC for a blog post reviewing Balaji Srinivasan&amp;rsquo;s post on network states.
If you get paid to write a book, or if you are regularly paid to write articles for a website, you are a writer.</description></item><item><title>033 - Moving</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/033-moving/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 11:13:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/033-moving/</guid><description>We just decided, yesterday, to move to New York City a month earlier than we had originally planned. Actually maybe two months earlier? Anyway, the point is we are starting the process right now, like today. We are selling most of our stuff, packing up the rest, and leaving California at the end of June. We are not coming back. Our apartment will be leased until the end of September, but we just want to get out and get to the city as soon as possible.</description></item><item><title>032 - Figuring Out Life</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/032-figuring-out-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:25:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/032-figuring-out-life/</guid><description>I think it&amp;rsquo;s a cultural meme where I come from that it takes a long time to figure out life. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s a cultural meme everywhere, and certainly not for all of time. Like there are cultures, and there have been times, where for the majority if not all people, what they will do in life is pretty much set from the time they are born.
Is figuring out life a relatively new concept?</description></item><item><title>031 - Gamification</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/031-gamification/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 20:47:49 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/031-gamification/</guid><description>You know every time I go to write one of these word vomits I get a little bit nervous. Like a little bit scared. I think it comes from a fear that I won&amp;rsquo;t have enough to say, or that it will take too much effort or too much time to write a thousands words.
Which is a little weird considering I&amp;rsquo;ve done thirty of these so far and none of them have been that hard.</description></item><item><title>030 - Wanting to Live Multiple Lives</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/030-wanting-to-live-multiple-lives/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 10:20:53 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/030-wanting-to-live-multiple-lives/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s really a bummer that you can only live one life. At least as far as I know you can only live one life. I assume if reincarnation were a thing then I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the first instance of the my being. My experience is that I have no past lives, and so I don&amp;rsquo;t expect to have future lives.
I mean maybe there could be reincarnation if it worked in a way that when you are living a life you don&amp;rsquo;t remember your past lives, and like when you die in one life maybe there is like an intermediate period where you return to your full, complete self in the void and you remember all of the lives that you&amp;rsquo;ve lived until that moment, and then you go into another life.</description></item><item><title>029 - When Things Actually Work Out</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/029-when-things-actually-work-out/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 16:04:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/029-when-things-actually-work-out/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a strange feeling &amp;ndash; an amazing feeling, to be sure &amp;ndash; when something that a few months ago you wished you had you suddenly have. My experience with this is not universal, but I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s probably in the majority. In my life, several things that I&amp;rsquo;ve really wanted to happen have happened, but probably more have not happened.
I did not go to a D1 college to play tennis.</description></item><item><title>028 - Vacation</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/028-vacation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 11:37:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/028-vacation/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been like two weeks since I did a word vomit. Maybe less, but it feels like a long time. I was doing them really consistently for more than a month so going more than like 2-3 days feels like ages.
Which is good, because it means I&amp;rsquo;m noticing the lack of them in my routine and it&amp;rsquo;s making me want to come back to writing them. I think that&amp;rsquo;s the sign of a habit that will stick around for a while.</description></item><item><title>027 - Trusting the Process</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/027-trusting-the-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 10:44:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/027-trusting-the-process/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a really big fan of trusting the process. It&amp;rsquo;s a phrase I invoke when someone is not sure that we&amp;rsquo;re doing the right thing because results haven&amp;rsquo;t materialized yet. And the idea behind trusting the process is that the process make sense from first principles. The results will come because we can predict from first principles that this process will generate those results.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good mental model for doing things that take a long time.</description></item><item><title>026 - Reflections on 1-25</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/026-reflections-on-1-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 18:00:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/026-reflections-on-1-25/</guid><description>This is my 26th word vomit, which means I&amp;rsquo;ve done 25 already. I thought it would be good to do a reflection on what it&amp;rsquo;s been like so far.
For starters, I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I&amp;rsquo;m still doing it! I start lots of projects and I also quit lots of projects before they become anything significant. I know it&amp;rsquo;s all relative, but writing 25,000 words of stream of consciousness journalling over the course of about a month is significant to me.</description></item><item><title>025 - Random I</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/025-random-i/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 21:20:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/025-random-i/</guid><description>This word vomit has no topic because there&amp;rsquo;s nothing obvious on my mind that I want to write about, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t written one in days and so I feel the need to get back to it.
I&amp;rsquo;m kind of settling into my &amp;ldquo;explore&amp;rdquo; phase. I wrote about this a few entries back, but basically I want to spend some time looking for the next fulfilling thing to do with my life.</description></item><item><title>024 - Is It a Poor Craftsman That Blames His Tools</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/024-is-it-a-poor-craftsman-that-blames-his-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 22:14:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/024-is-it-a-poor-craftsman-that-blames-his-tools/</guid><description>There is this saying that &amp;ldquo;It is a poor craftsman that blames his tools.&amp;rdquo; I think it means that having done a poor job at something, it is a bad excuse to blame the tools you were using to do the job. As it to say you would have been able to do a good job, if it were not for the short comings of these tools which you did not make and so are not accountable for.</description></item><item><title>023 - What Is It About Reading</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/023-what-is-it-about-reading/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 20:55:47 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/023-what-is-it-about-reading/</guid><description>There is something about people that grew up reading a lot. Or I guess even just someone who has been reading a lot for a while. It makes them different than other people. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what the difference is, but I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s real.
Now, reading a lot is relative. I think I used to read a lot, probably hit 40 or 50 books a year at my peak in late middle school, early high school.</description></item><item><title>022 - Strategy, Goals, and Tactics</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/022-strategy-goals-and-tactics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 19:47:13 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/022-strategy-goals-and-tactics/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in a sort of quiet period in my life where I&amp;rsquo;m not building anything. At least in the way I&amp;rsquo;m usually building something, which is writing a lot of code and making it run on the internet.
In the past couple weeks, and going forward for an indefinite amount of time, I&amp;rsquo;ll be just searching, chilling, playing, thinking. The idea is that I&amp;rsquo;ll find some object level thing I&amp;rsquo;m interested in pursuing.</description></item><item><title>021 - It's Not Enough to Understand Infinite Games</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/021-its-not-enough-to-understand-infinite-games/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 12:49:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/021-its-not-enough-to-understand-infinite-games/</guid><description>Once you understand the concept of an infinite game, it&amp;rsquo;s not like you can just start playing one because you like the idea of it. You need to have a game to play. You need to have something that you like doing and that can fit the model of an infinite game.
Because the core part of being an infinite game player is that you enjoy the game so much that you just want to keep playing it.</description></item><item><title>020 - You Still Have to Play Finite Games</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/020-you-still-have-to-play-finite-games/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 09:44:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/020-you-still-have-to-play-finite-games/</guid><description>Even if you are an inifinite game player and fully grasp the continuum of chained finite games that comprise your domain, you still have to play finite games with finite game players. Maybe you could build like a commune of infinite game players and not have to encounter any finite game players, but then you&amp;rsquo;d be cutting yourself off from much of the world and it&amp;rsquo;s not worth it.
No, you have to play finite games with finite game players.</description></item><item><title>019 - Infinite Games</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/019-infinite-games/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 09:07:35 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/019-infinite-games/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned infinite games a few times before in word vomits, but I realize I haven&amp;rsquo;t dedicated a whole one to that concept yet. It&amp;rsquo;s about time, I&amp;rsquo;d say. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the ideas that I&amp;rsquo;m working my way around and through in mind my recently, because I think really understanding it will do a lot for my happiness and sense of fulfillment in life.
It will also probably help me figure out what to work on.</description></item><item><title>018 - Slack as Necessary Ingredient</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/018-slack-as-necessary-ingredient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 22:18:06 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/018-slack-as-necessary-ingredient/</guid><description>This week at work is a return to the idea that slack is a necessary ingredient for outsized success. There are a lot of things I see around work that can be improved. And that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even be that hard to improve them. Just some focused and careful thought to research and design solutions, and then some straightforward implementation.
I&amp;rsquo;m talking about like code review tools, static analysis, performance improvements in different areas of the data pipeline, development process improvements like automated deploys and faster builds, etc etc etc.</description></item><item><title>017 - More on Play</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/017-more-on-play/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 17:53:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/017-more-on-play/</guid><description>If I&amp;rsquo;m going to make any big leaps with this idea of implementing play in the rest of my life, I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to do real thinking about it. Like, what does it apply to? how do I incorporate it? does incorporating it in different parts of life look different? what does it mean for my relationships with other people? will it change my demeanor and be weird for those around me?</description></item><item><title>016 - Exploring Playfulness</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/016-exploring-playfulness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 13:55:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/016-exploring-playfulness/</guid><description>I was not expecting to make any sort of breakthrough when I was writing yesterday. I was kind of thinking to myself over the past few days &amp;ldquo;when are you supposed to see results?&amp;rdquo; about this writing thing. This word vomit thing. Visa says it helped him work out a bunch of personal issues like self-confidence and self-love. Basically when I got like the tenth one, I started wondering how it would happen.</description></item><item><title>015 - Need to Learn How to Play</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/015-need-to-learn-how-to-play/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 15:56:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/015-need-to-learn-how-to-play/</guid><description>I feel like the central tension in my life is not feeling like I&amp;rsquo;m working towards the right thing. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the right thing is, and maybe I am doing things that are bringing me closer to it, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t always feel like it.
Maybe it felt like it when I won the $100 BTC from the most recent 1729 task. Because one thing I want to be good at is writing on the internet, and winning money by writing good things on the internet seems like nice validation of that goal.</description></item><item><title>014 - Activation Energy</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/014-activation-energy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 18:27:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/014-activation-energy/</guid><description>There is this concept of activation energy that seems super important to me, and activation energy actually describes it pretty well, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see people talking about it very much (if at all, can&amp;rsquo;t recall any examples), and definitely don&amp;rsquo;t see people using this metaphor.
What is &amp;ldquo;activation energy&amp;rdquo; in this context? It&amp;rsquo;s the energy you need to muster to start doing some task. Usually it&amp;rsquo;s a work thing, like sitting down to work in the morning, or doing a chore like washing the dishes, or doing your taxes, or working out.</description></item><item><title>013 - Is The Internet A Cybernetic Appendage</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/013-is-the-internet-a-cybernetic-appendage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:47:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/013-is-the-internet-a-cybernetic-appendage/</guid><description>Some people make this reference to an idea that the internet, or actually maybe more often the referent is the phone, anyway that this thing is a cybernetic appendage. Like it&amp;rsquo;s actually an extension of your body or mind and it&amp;rsquo;s kind of weird because we are all on the same internet and so we share this extension of our mind.
Everyone has different experiences on the internet, so it&amp;rsquo;s not the same extension for everyone.</description></item><item><title>012 - Changing Yourself If It Makes Sense</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/012-changing-yourself-if-it-makes-sense/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 09:26:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/012-changing-yourself-if-it-makes-sense/</guid><description>When I was a kid I don&amp;rsquo;t think I had much sense of identity. I just kind of went to school and played tennis (so I guess I&amp;rsquo;m talking from like 5 years old to maybe 11 or 12), hung out with friends, read books. Looking back I basically consider myself a biological machine responding mechanically to the inputs of my environment. There was very little of what I would now call &amp;ldquo;free will&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;rational agency&amp;rdquo; going into my decisions about what I liked or how I liked to spend my time.</description></item><item><title>011 - Living in the Moment</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/011-living-in-the-moment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 08:56:35 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/011-living-in-the-moment/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m that good at living in the moment. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I have a great definition of even what it means, but I have a feeling I&amp;rsquo;m not that good at it. I&amp;rsquo;m always thinking about the future. Mostly I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about projects I have going on and what&amp;rsquo;s the next step that I can work on to make progress. And I even spend a lot of time brainstorming potential projects.</description></item><item><title>010 - Body Image</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/010-body-image/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 20:14:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/010-body-image/</guid><description>Body image is something I haven&amp;rsquo;t really had to think serious about before. I consider this a lucky accident mostly. I was born with good genes and started effectively working out extremely hard when I was like 12. My sport was tennis, I think around 11 or 12 was when I started going to a tennis clinic once a week. It was for 2 hours I think and as part of it I did a lot of running.</description></item><item><title>009 - Food Management</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/009-food-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 13:28:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/009-food-management/</guid><description>Food is one of those things that&amp;rsquo;s just in the background of life. For me, at least. I realize that&amp;rsquo;s not how other people relate to food. But at the moment, food is a necessity but not something I like spending time thinking about and managing. But I see room for improvement there.
I don&amp;rsquo;t want my relationship with food to be that it&amp;rsquo;s an afterthought. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to not spend time on food.</description></item><item><title>008 - The Internet Is Magic</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/008-the-internet-is-magic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 16:11:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/008-the-internet-is-magic/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s 3:49pm on a Friday and I&amp;rsquo;m so tired but I feel like I just want to write a word vomit. It&amp;rsquo;s like there&amp;rsquo;s stuff inside my head that' making me tired? I don&amp;rsquo;t know how that works. It feels like if I just get it out then my mind will be more clear and I&amp;rsquo;ll be more with it. I&amp;rsquo;ll have more clarity. Feel lighter in my body.
Part of the problem no doubt is that I ate a bunch of pasta for lunch.</description></item><item><title>007 - Pseudonymity</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/007-pseudonymity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 12:01:55 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/007-pseudonymity/</guid><description>Pseudonymity is being known under a name different than your given name. When I think about names, and being known under a different name than my &amp;ldquo;birth name&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;given name&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;state name&amp;rdquo;, I realize that names are not special. Like, &amp;ldquo;Matt Roll&amp;rdquo; is not more special than some name I make up and use to talk to people online. I mean ok, maybe there is a good case at this moment in 2021 why my given name is more special than some name I make up and use to talk to people online.</description></item><item><title>006 - Hobbies</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/006-hobbies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 21:00:50 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/006-hobbies/</guid><description>I definitely like the idea of hobbies. Some activity you do just for fun, not for any future gain. Well, maybe you think there is future gain, like it you get really good at the hobby then it will be more enjoyable to practice it. But not future gain as in you think you will be able to like sell your paintings for lots of money and that&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;re going to realize your financial life goals.</description></item><item><title>005 - Making Friends</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/005-making-friends/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 21:09:08 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/005-making-friends/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always had friends, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never put much effort into making friends. Ah, ok, that&amp;rsquo;s already not true. In eighth grade I decided for some deranged reason that only makes sense in the mind of a teenager that I wanted to be popular. And so I started putting a lot of effort into becoming friends with the popular kids. I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure at this point how I bootstrapped that endeavor.</description></item><item><title>004 - Crypto</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/004-crypto/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 15:05:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/004-crypto/</guid><description>When I got to college in 2012 I had already read Cryptonomicon and it was my favorite book. At some point that year I also found out about bitcoin, which was obviously like the ideas in Cryptonomicon manifest in the real world. Real world digital gold. I thought it was really cool, and I tried to download the software and start mining bitcoin from my laptop in my freshman dorm room.</description></item><item><title>003 - Coffee</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/003-coffee/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 09:38:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/003-coffee/</guid><description>Coffee went from being something I knew about but had no experience with, to a daily ritual and something I have a real love for, in like the span of a couple months. It was freshman year of college, and the dining hall had free coffee, and I would take it with some cream and sugar. My friend Joe and I would kind of bond over coffee, I think he was already a coffee drinker and the reason I took an interest to it might have been a way to have something we could share and talk about.</description></item><item><title>002 - Education</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/002-education/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 22:02:36 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/002-education/</guid><description>I want to write about education because I think I bundle too many ideas into that word, and I want to tease them apart. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any coherent positions on &amp;ldquo;education&amp;rdquo; mostly because it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any crisp meaning in my head.
Ok, what are the concepts that I associate with the word &amp;ldquo;education&amp;rdquo;?
First is the school system in the United States. I get a sort of visual of lots of different school units spread over a large geography when I think of the term &amp;ldquo;education&amp;rdquo;, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s how my mind manifests the idea of the United States primary school system.</description></item><item><title>001 - Why am I writing?</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:04:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</guid><description>This is the first post in a 1,000 post project. A project to write a million words. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if those words are good, mediocre, amazing, or awful. It just matters that they exist. Because if they exist, it means I forced my brain to make a million words come out of my brain, through my fingers and the keyboard, into a computer, and onto the internet. And if that has happened, then I&amp;rsquo;ve probably learned a few things about myself, about writing, about consistency, about practice.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:04:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/about/</guid><description>This is a project to write 1,000,000 words.
I feel like I have a lot to say, both because there are things I want to share and because there are things I think I will only figure out through the course of writing.
But at the moment it&amp;rsquo;s difficult for me to get ideas out of my head and onto the page. The ideas in my head feel like water, and they are trying to flow downstream to the page, but the stream is not wide enough, or there is blockage, like sticks and leaves keeping the idea-water from moving quickly through the channel.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/archives/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/archives/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>