<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>stress on babble</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/stress/</link><description>Recent content in stress on babble</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 13:55:10 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/stress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>016 - Exploring Playfulness</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/016-exploring-playfulness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 13:55:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/016-exploring-playfulness/</guid><description>I was not expecting to make any sort of breakthrough when I was writing yesterday. I was kind of thinking to myself over the past few days &amp;ldquo;when are you supposed to see results?&amp;rdquo; about this writing thing. This word vomit thing. Visa says it helped him work out a bunch of personal issues like self-confidence and self-love. Basically when I got like the tenth one, I started wondering how it would happen.</description></item><item><title>015 - Need to Learn How to Play</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/015-need-to-learn-how-to-play/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 15:56:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/015-need-to-learn-how-to-play/</guid><description>I feel like the central tension in my life is not feeling like I&amp;rsquo;m working towards the right thing. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the right thing is, and maybe I am doing things that are bringing me closer to it, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t always feel like it.
Maybe it felt like it when I won the $100 BTC from the most recent 1729 task. Because one thing I want to be good at is writing on the internet, and winning money by writing good things on the internet seems like nice validation of that goal.</description></item><item><title>014 - Activation Energy</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/014-activation-energy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 18:27:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/014-activation-energy/</guid><description>There is this concept of activation energy that seems super important to me, and activation energy actually describes it pretty well, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see people talking about it very much (if at all, can&amp;rsquo;t recall any examples), and definitely don&amp;rsquo;t see people using this metaphor.
What is &amp;ldquo;activation energy&amp;rdquo; in this context? It&amp;rsquo;s the energy you need to muster to start doing some task. Usually it&amp;rsquo;s a work thing, like sitting down to work in the morning, or doing a chore like washing the dishes, or doing your taxes, or working out.</description></item><item><title>009 - Food Management</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/009-food-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 13:28:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/009-food-management/</guid><description>Food is one of those things that&amp;rsquo;s just in the background of life. For me, at least. I realize that&amp;rsquo;s not how other people relate to food. But at the moment, food is a necessity but not something I like spending time thinking about and managing. But I see room for improvement there.
I don&amp;rsquo;t want my relationship with food to be that it&amp;rsquo;s an afterthought. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to not spend time on food.</description></item><item><title>006 - Hobbies</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/006-hobbies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 21:00:50 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/006-hobbies/</guid><description>I definitely like the idea of hobbies. Some activity you do just for fun, not for any future gain. Well, maybe you think there is future gain, like it you get really good at the hobby then it will be more enjoyable to practice it. But not future gain as in you think you will be able to like sell your paintings for lots of money and that&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;re going to realize your financial life goals.</description></item></channel></rss>