<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reading on babble</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/reading/</link><description>Recent content in reading on babble</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 21:20:11 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>025 - Random I</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/025-random-i/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 21:20:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/025-random-i/</guid><description>This word vomit has no topic because there&amp;rsquo;s nothing obvious on my mind that I want to write about, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t written one in days and so I feel the need to get back to it.
I&amp;rsquo;m kind of settling into my &amp;ldquo;explore&amp;rdquo; phase. I wrote about this a few entries back, but basically I want to spend some time looking for the next fulfilling thing to do with my life.</description></item><item><title>023 - What Is It About Reading</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/023-what-is-it-about-reading/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 20:55:47 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/023-what-is-it-about-reading/</guid><description>There is something about people that grew up reading a lot. Or I guess even just someone who has been reading a lot for a while. It makes them different than other people. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what the difference is, but I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s real.
Now, reading a lot is relative. I think I used to read a lot, probably hit 40 or 50 books a year at my peak in late middle school, early high school.</description></item><item><title>006 - Hobbies</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/006-hobbies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 21:00:50 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/006-hobbies/</guid><description>I definitely like the idea of hobbies. Some activity you do just for fun, not for any future gain. Well, maybe you think there is future gain, like it you get really good at the hobby then it will be more enjoyable to practice it. But not future gain as in you think you will be able to like sell your paintings for lots of money and that&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;re going to realize your financial life goals.</description></item><item><title>005 - Making Friends</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/005-making-friends/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 21:09:08 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/005-making-friends/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always had friends, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never put much effort into making friends. Ah, ok, that&amp;rsquo;s already not true. In eighth grade I decided for some deranged reason that only makes sense in the mind of a teenager that I wanted to be popular. And so I started putting a lot of effort into becoming friends with the popular kids. I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure at this point how I bootstrapped that endeavor.</description></item><item><title>001 - Why am I writing?</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:04:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</guid><description>This is the first post in a 1,000 post project. A project to write a million words. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if those words are good, mediocre, amazing, or awful. It just matters that they exist. Because if they exist, it means I forced my brain to make a million words come out of my brain, through my fingers and the keyboard, into a computer, and onto the internet. And if that has happened, then I&amp;rsquo;ve probably learned a few things about myself, about writing, about consistency, about practice.</description></item></channel></rss>