<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>infinite games on babble</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/infinite-games/</link><description>Recent content in infinite games on babble</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 09:44:33 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/infinite-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>020 - You Still Have to Play Finite Games</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/020-you-still-have-to-play-finite-games/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 09:44:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/020-you-still-have-to-play-finite-games/</guid><description>Even if you are an inifinite game player and fully grasp the continuum of chained finite games that comprise your domain, you still have to play finite games with finite game players. Maybe you could build like a commune of infinite game players and not have to encounter any finite game players, but then you&amp;rsquo;d be cutting yourself off from much of the world and it&amp;rsquo;s not worth it.
No, you have to play finite games with finite game players.</description></item><item><title>019 - Infinite Games</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/019-infinite-games/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 09:07:35 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/019-infinite-games/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned infinite games a few times before in word vomits, but I realize I haven&amp;rsquo;t dedicated a whole one to that concept yet. It&amp;rsquo;s about time, I&amp;rsquo;d say. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the ideas that I&amp;rsquo;m working my way around and through in mind my recently, because I think really understanding it will do a lot for my happiness and sense of fulfillment in life.
It will also probably help me figure out what to work on.</description></item><item><title>017 - More on Play</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/017-more-on-play/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 17:53:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/017-more-on-play/</guid><description>If I&amp;rsquo;m going to make any big leaps with this idea of implementing play in the rest of my life, I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to do real thinking about it. Like, what does it apply to? how do I incorporate it? does incorporating it in different parts of life look different? what does it mean for my relationships with other people? will it change my demeanor and be weird for those around me?</description></item><item><title>016 - Exploring Playfulness</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/016-exploring-playfulness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 13:55:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/016-exploring-playfulness/</guid><description>I was not expecting to make any sort of breakthrough when I was writing yesterday. I was kind of thinking to myself over the past few days &amp;ldquo;when are you supposed to see results?&amp;rdquo; about this writing thing. This word vomit thing. Visa says it helped him work out a bunch of personal issues like self-confidence and self-love. Basically when I got like the tenth one, I started wondering how it would happen.</description></item><item><title>015 - Need to Learn How to Play</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/015-need-to-learn-how-to-play/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 15:56:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/015-need-to-learn-how-to-play/</guid><description>I feel like the central tension in my life is not feeling like I&amp;rsquo;m working towards the right thing. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the right thing is, and maybe I am doing things that are bringing me closer to it, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t always feel like it.
Maybe it felt like it when I won the $100 BTC from the most recent 1729 task. Because one thing I want to be good at is writing on the internet, and winning money by writing good things on the internet seems like nice validation of that goal.</description></item></channel></rss>