<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>writing on babble</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/writing/</link><description>Recent content in writing on babble</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 14:03:27 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>042 - What I Think About</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/042-what-i-think-about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 14:03:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/042-what-i-think-about/</guid><description>Sasha Chapin says that if you think you have writer&amp;rsquo;s block you actually are just lying to yourself about who you are and what you think about. That if you feel like you don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to write about, you&amp;rsquo;re wrong because obviously there are thoughts floating around in your head and you should just look at them and put them down on paper roughly in the order they occur to you.</description></item><item><title>041 - Welcome Back</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/041-welcome-back/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 16:08:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/041-welcome-back/</guid><description>Ok, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been on something of a hiatus from this thing. I wrote the last post sitting at the San Francisco airport waiting for the flight that would take me back to the east coast for the foreseeable future. (And honestly I can&amp;rsquo;t see myself living on the west coast again.)
That kicked off a move to New York City that has taken up pretty much 100% of my time since then.</description></item><item><title>036 - The Writing Brain I'm Trying to Build</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/036-the-writing-brain-im-trying-to-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 20:49:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/036-the-writing-brain-im-trying-to-build/</guid><description>There is a type of brain that can just push words out onto the page at an alarming rate with relative ease. I want that brain. I don&amp;rsquo;t currently have that brain, but this project is me putting time and energy directly toward a future where that is the brain I have. I just think there is so much interesting stuff that gets lost because only so much can fit inside your head and so you eventually forget and move onto other interesting things without properly documenting what you were thinking about previously.</description></item><item><title>035 - Writing Fiction</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/035-writing-fiction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 21:28:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/035-writing-fiction/</guid><description>Fiction is what got me into reading. As a kid I fell in love with stories written down as words on pages. I think this is a pretty common theme among people who love reading, but something about books is magical. And I saw that magic early on.
At some point, I think maybe it was middle school, I got into science fiction. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the first science fiction I read was.</description></item><item><title>034 - Identity as a Writer</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/034-identity-as-a-writer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:14:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/034-identity-as-a-writer/</guid><description>What makes someone &amp;ldquo;a writer.&amp;rdquo; Like, being &amp;ldquo;a writer&amp;rdquo; is an occupation, certainly. If you have been paid for something you wrote then you can consider yourself a writer. Actually as I write that I realize that I have been paid for something I wrote: $100 BTC for a blog post reviewing Balaji Srinivasan&amp;rsquo;s post on network states.
If you get paid to write a book, or if you are regularly paid to write articles for a website, you are a writer.</description></item><item><title>026 - Reflections on 1-25</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/026-reflections-on-1-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 18:00:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/026-reflections-on-1-25/</guid><description>This is my 26th word vomit, which means I&amp;rsquo;ve done 25 already. I thought it would be good to do a reflection on what it&amp;rsquo;s been like so far.
For starters, I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I&amp;rsquo;m still doing it! I start lots of projects and I also quit lots of projects before they become anything significant. I know it&amp;rsquo;s all relative, but writing 25,000 words of stream of consciousness journalling over the course of about a month is significant to me.</description></item><item><title>001 - Why am I writing?</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:04:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</guid><description>This is the first post in a 1,000 post project. A project to write a million words. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if those words are good, mediocre, amazing, or awful. It just matters that they exist. Because if they exist, it means I forced my brain to make a million words come out of my brain, through my fingers and the keyboard, into a computer, and onto the internet. And if that has happened, then I&amp;rsquo;ve probably learned a few things about myself, about writing, about consistency, about practice.</description></item></channel></rss>