<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>writing on babble</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/writing/</link><description>Recent content in writing on babble</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:14:14 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>034 - Identity as a Writer</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/034-identity-as-a-writer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:14:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/034-identity-as-a-writer/</guid><description>What makes someone &amp;ldquo;a writer.&amp;rdquo; Like, being &amp;ldquo;a writer&amp;rdquo; is an occupation, certainly. If you have been paid for something you wrote then you can consider yourself a writer. Actually as I write that I realize that I have been paid for something I wrote: $100 BTC for a blog post reviewing Balaji Srinivasan&amp;rsquo;s post on network states.
If you get paid to write a book, or if you are regularly paid to write articles for a website, you are a writer.</description></item><item><title>026 - Reflections on 1-25</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/026-reflections-on-1-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 18:00:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/026-reflections-on-1-25/</guid><description>This is my 26th word vomit, which means I&amp;rsquo;ve done 25 already. I thought it would be good to do a reflection on what it&amp;rsquo;s been like so far.
For starters, I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I&amp;rsquo;m still doing it! I start lots of projects and I also quit lots of projects before they become anything significant. I know it&amp;rsquo;s all relative, but writing 25,000 words of stream of consciousness journalling over the course of about a month is significant to me.</description></item><item><title>001 - Why am I writing?</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:04:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</guid><description>This is the first post in a 1,000 post project. A project to write a million words. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if those words are good, mediocre, amazing, or awful. It just matters that they exist. Because if they exist, it means I forced my brain to make a million words come out of my brain, through my fingers and the keyboard, into a computer, and onto the internet. And if that has happened, then I&amp;rsquo;ve probably learned a few things about myself, about writing, about consistency, about practice.</description></item></channel></rss>