<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on babble</title><link>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on babble</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 09:38:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>003 - Coffee</title><link>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/003-coffee/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 09:38:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/003-coffee/</guid><description>Coffee went from being something I knew about but had no experience with, to a daily ritual and something I have a real love for, in like the span of a couple months. It was freshman year of college, and the dining hall had free coffee, and I would take it with some cream and sugar. My friend Joe and I would kind of bond over coffee, I think he was already a coffee drinker and the reason I took an interest to it might have been a way to have something we could share and talk about.</description></item><item><title>002 - Education</title><link>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/002-education/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 22:02:36 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/002-education/</guid><description>I want to write about education because I think I bundle too many ideas into that word, and I want to tease them apart. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any coherent positions on &amp;ldquo;education&amp;rdquo; mostly because it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any crisp meaning in my head.
Ok, what are the concepts that I associate with the word &amp;ldquo;education&amp;rdquo;?
First is the school system in the United States. I get a sort of visual of lots of different school units spread over a large geography when I think of the term &amp;ldquo;education&amp;rdquo;, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s how my mind manifests the idea of the United States primary school system.</description></item><item><title>001 - Why am I writing?</title><link>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:04:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://mroll.github.io/babble.matthewroll.com/blog/hello/</guid><description>This is the first post in a 1,000 post project. A project to write a million words. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if those words are good, mediocre, amazing, or awful. It just matters that they exist. Because if they exist, it means I forced my brain to make a million words come out of my brain, through my fingers and the keyboard, into a computer, and onto the internet. And if that has happened, then I&amp;rsquo;ve probably learned a few things about myself, about writing, about consistency, about practice.</description></item></channel></rss>