<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>future on babble</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/future/</link><description>Recent content in future on babble</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 11:13:11 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/future/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>033 - Moving</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/033-moving/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 11:13:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/033-moving/</guid><description>We just decided, yesterday, to move to New York City a month earlier than we had originally planned. Actually maybe two months earlier? Anyway, the point is we are starting the process right now, like today. We are selling most of our stuff, packing up the rest, and leaving California at the end of June. We are not coming back. Our apartment will be leased until the end of September, but we just want to get out and get to the city as soon as possible.</description></item><item><title>032 - Figuring Out Life</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/032-figuring-out-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:25:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/032-figuring-out-life/</guid><description>I think it&amp;rsquo;s a cultural meme where I come from that it takes a long time to figure out life. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s a cultural meme everywhere, and certainly not for all of time. Like there are cultures, and there have been times, where for the majority if not all people, what they will do in life is pretty much set from the time they are born.
Is figuring out life a relatively new concept?</description></item><item><title>008 - The Internet Is Magic</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/008-the-internet-is-magic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 16:11:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/008-the-internet-is-magic/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s 3:49pm on a Friday and I&amp;rsquo;m so tired but I feel like I just want to write a word vomit. It&amp;rsquo;s like there&amp;rsquo;s stuff inside my head that' making me tired? I don&amp;rsquo;t know how that works. It feels like if I just get it out then my mind will be more clear and I&amp;rsquo;ll be more with it. I&amp;rsquo;ll have more clarity. Feel lighter in my body.
Part of the problem no doubt is that I ate a bunch of pasta for lunch.</description></item><item><title>006 - Hobbies</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/006-hobbies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 21:00:50 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/006-hobbies/</guid><description>I definitely like the idea of hobbies. Some activity you do just for fun, not for any future gain. Well, maybe you think there is future gain, like it you get really good at the hobby then it will be more enjoyable to practice it. But not future gain as in you think you will be able to like sell your paintings for lots of money and that&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;re going to realize your financial life goals.</description></item></channel></rss>