<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>future on babble</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/future/</link><description>Recent content in future on babble</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 11:30:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/future/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>048 - Writers Block</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/048-writers-block/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 11:30:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/048-writers-block/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s not that I have writer&amp;rsquo;s block so much as I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to write what I want to write. That&amp;rsquo;s not what I think of as writer&amp;rsquo;s block, anyway. What writer&amp;rsquo;s block is to me is the inability write, period.
Which is not what I have because I&amp;rsquo;ve actually been writing a fair amount all the way through this whole thing of not being able to write.
I keep coming back to the thing Sasha Chapin wrote about &amp;ldquo;writer&amp;rsquo;s block&amp;rdquo; which is that if you have writer&amp;rsquo;s block then it&amp;rsquo;s because you are embarrassed about what you think about, or something like that.</description></item><item><title>043 - Something of a Life Plan</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/043-something-of-a-life-plan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 15:01:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/043-something-of-a-life-plan/</guid><description>Something that I&amp;rsquo;ve thought a fair amount about over the past few years but haven&amp;rsquo;t put into writing as far as I can remember is my high level, general life plan for the next ten years.
It&amp;rsquo;s not super detailed and doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover everything in life, and actually now that I think about it it&amp;rsquo;s actually mostly just about making money. But since what I do to make money and how much money I make has a massive impact on how I live my life and what options are open for living my life, I kind of think of it as a general life plan.</description></item><item><title>040 - Moving on From California</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/040-moving-on-from-california/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 22:40:52 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/040-moving-on-from-california/</guid><description>Today is my last day in California. I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in the SFO airport waiting for my flight back east to board. Figured it was a good time to write a word vomit. Maybe process some stuff that I&amp;rsquo;m feeling.
The thing is I&amp;rsquo;m not feeling anything significant. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to go back east, back home, is really how I think about it. I never got to feel like Cali was home.</description></item><item><title>038 - On Taste</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/038-on-taste/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 21:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/038-on-taste/</guid><description>There is a great Ira Glass quote about taste and how you build it. It rings true to my experience. Basically it says that even people with killer taste cannot produce up to their own standards when they are just starting out. They have a vision for something great, and they try to build it, but it turns out inevitably to look like shit.
This can be discouraging, but fear not, goes the quote.</description></item><item><title>037 - Maybe I Should Just Get Started</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/037-maybe-i-should-just-get-started/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 18:48:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/037-maybe-i-should-just-get-started/</guid><description>I have this idea that I&amp;rsquo;ll eventually start some big project that will be really technically interesting and challenging, and I&amp;rsquo;ll work on it for years and it will pay my bills and maybe even make me rich.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently not doing that, like not doing any work on that, because I feel like I have to do something else first. I feel like I have to do some sort of stepping stone project.</description></item><item><title>033 - Moving</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/033-moving/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 11:13:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/033-moving/</guid><description>We just decided, yesterday, to move to New York City a month earlier than we had originally planned. Actually maybe two months earlier? Anyway, the point is we are starting the process right now, like today. We are selling most of our stuff, packing up the rest, and leaving California at the end of June. We are not coming back. Our apartment will be leased until the end of September, but we just want to get out and get to the city as soon as possible.</description></item><item><title>032 - Figuring Out Life</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/032-figuring-out-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:25:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/032-figuring-out-life/</guid><description>I think it&amp;rsquo;s a cultural meme where I come from that it takes a long time to figure out life. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s a cultural meme everywhere, and certainly not for all of time. Like there are cultures, and there have been times, where for the majority if not all people, what they will do in life is pretty much set from the time they are born.
Is figuring out life a relatively new concept?</description></item><item><title>008 - The Internet Is Magic</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/008-the-internet-is-magic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 16:11:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/008-the-internet-is-magic/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s 3:49pm on a Friday and I&amp;rsquo;m so tired but I feel like I just want to write a word vomit. It&amp;rsquo;s like there&amp;rsquo;s stuff inside my head that' making me tired? I don&amp;rsquo;t know how that works. It feels like if I just get it out then my mind will be more clear and I&amp;rsquo;ll be more with it. I&amp;rsquo;ll have more clarity. Feel lighter in my body.
Part of the problem no doubt is that I ate a bunch of pasta for lunch.</description></item><item><title>006 - Hobbies</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/006-hobbies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 21:00:50 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/006-hobbies/</guid><description>I definitely like the idea of hobbies. Some activity you do just for fun, not for any future gain. Well, maybe you think there is future gain, like it you get really good at the hobby then it will be more enjoyable to practice it. But not future gain as in you think you will be able to like sell your paintings for lots of money and that&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;re going to realize your financial life goals.</description></item></channel></rss>