<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>goals on babble</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/goals/</link><description>Recent content in goals on babble</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 20:49:22 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://babble.matthewroll.com/tags/goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>036 - The Writing Brain I'm Trying to Build</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/036-the-writing-brain-im-trying-to-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 20:49:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/036-the-writing-brain-im-trying-to-build/</guid><description>There is a type of brain that can just push words out onto the page at an alarming rate with relative ease. I want that brain. I don&amp;rsquo;t currently have that brain, but this project is me putting time and energy directly toward a future where that is the brain I have. I just think there is so much interesting stuff that gets lost because only so much can fit inside your head and so you eventually forget and move onto other interesting things without properly documenting what you were thinking about previously.</description></item><item><title>031 - Gamification</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/031-gamification/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 20:47:49 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/031-gamification/</guid><description>You know every time I go to write one of these word vomits I get a little bit nervous. Like a little bit scared. I think it comes from a fear that I won&amp;rsquo;t have enough to say, or that it will take too much effort or too much time to write a thousands words.
Which is a little weird considering I&amp;rsquo;ve done thirty of these so far and none of them have been that hard.</description></item><item><title>029 - When Things Actually Work Out</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/029-when-things-actually-work-out/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 16:04:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/029-when-things-actually-work-out/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a strange feeling &amp;ndash; an amazing feeling, to be sure &amp;ndash; when something that a few months ago you wished you had you suddenly have. My experience with this is not universal, but I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s probably in the majority. In my life, several things that I&amp;rsquo;ve really wanted to happen have happened, but probably more have not happened.
I did not go to a D1 college to play tennis.</description></item><item><title>027 - Trusting the Process</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/027-trusting-the-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 10:44:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/027-trusting-the-process/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a really big fan of trusting the process. It&amp;rsquo;s a phrase I invoke when someone is not sure that we&amp;rsquo;re doing the right thing because results haven&amp;rsquo;t materialized yet. And the idea behind trusting the process is that the process make sense from first principles. The results will come because we can predict from first principles that this process will generate those results.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good mental model for doing things that take a long time.</description></item><item><title>022 - Strategy, Goals, and Tactics</title><link>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/022-strategy-goals-and-tactics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 19:47:13 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://babble.matthewroll.com/blog/022-strategy-goals-and-tactics/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in a sort of quiet period in my life where I&amp;rsquo;m not building anything. At least in the way I&amp;rsquo;m usually building something, which is writing a lot of code and making it run on the internet.
In the past couple weeks, and going forward for an indefinite amount of time, I&amp;rsquo;ll be just searching, chilling, playing, thinking. The idea is that I&amp;rsquo;ll find some object level thing I&amp;rsquo;m interested in pursuing.</description></item></channel></rss>